http://www.ipaustralia.gov.au/about-us/agency-overview/privacy-policy

Privacy | IP Australia
Skip to main content
IP Australia is open for business and continues to be committed to its customers and stakeholders. We are closely monitoring the latest information about the Novel Coronavirus (COVID-19) outbreak. Please refer to the Business continuity and the Coronavirus disease (COVID-19) outbreak page last updated 14 September 2020 for the most up to date information. We acknowledge these are challenging and uncertain times for everyone.
For information on new government support for business see Business.gov.au.
Close
About us
Customer Service Charter
News
Contact us
Careers
Enter your keywords
Search
Link: ONLINE SERVICES
Home
PatentsPatentsIf you have a device, substance, method or process that is new, inventive and useful, you may need a patent. Find out what patents are and what’s involved in the application and management process.Learn moreUnderstanding patentsPatent basics
Types of patents
Time and costs
Searching patents
Engaging an attorney toolkit
Applying for a patentStandard patent application process
Innovation patent application process
Provisional application process
International Application process
What to include in your application
Portal for small and medium enterprises (SMEs)
Managing your patentMaintaining your patent
Amending your patent
Enforcing your patent
Patent response times
Search patents
Apply for a patent
Patent examination manual
Patent case studies
Download supplement journals
Patent Analytics Hub
Trade marksTrade marksIf you want to distinguish your goods, services (or both) from those of another business, you may need a trade mark. Find out what trade marks are and what’s involved in the application and management process.Learn moreUnderstanding trade marksTrade mark basics
Benefits of trade marks
Trade marks examination process
Geographical Indications
Applying for a trade markDecide if you have a trade mark
Understanding goods and services
Search
How to apply
Application outcome
Managing your trade markUsing and maintaining your trade mark
Introducing the Trade Mark COVID-19 Helpline
Trade marks and oppositions
International trade marks
Unsolicited invoices
Trade Marks Response Times
Search trade marks
Apply for a trade mark
Trade mark examination manual
Trade mark costs
Trade mark case studies
Renew your Trade mark
DesignsDesignsIf you want to protect the unique visual appearance of a product, you may need design rights. Find out what they are and what’s involved in the application and management process.Learn moreUnderstanding designsThe benefits of protecting your design
The difference between designs rights and other IP rights
What a design right is
Applying for a designChecklist for applying for a design right
Design right costs
The process of applying for a design right
Manage your designProtect your design
Renew your design
Legislation explained
Amend your design
Search designs
Apply for a design
Designs examination manual
Design fees
Designs case studies
Searchable designs journals
Plant breeder's rightsPlant breeder's rightsIf you have developed, or are developing a new plant variety, you may need plant breeder’s rights. Find out what they are and what’s involved in the application and management process.Learn moreUnderstanding PBRPBR basics
PBR in detail
PBR and other IP rights
PBR time and costs
Applying for PBRDecide if you have a PBR
Search for a PBR
Qualified person
Application part 1
Growing trial
PBR Journals
Understanding IPUnderstanding IPFind out what you need to know to get started and progress your intellectual property (IP) journey including tips on taking your idea to market in Australia and abroad.Learn moreGetting started with IPIP Explained
Educational materials and resources
Protecting your IP
Types of IP
IP Contract Generator
IP for Digital business
Indigenous Knowledge
Commercialise your IPCommercialisation steps to consider
IP Toolkit
IP in everyday life
IP infringementIP infringementFind out what to do if someone is infringing on your intellectual property (IP), how to avoid infringing on someone else’s IP and what to do about unsolicited IP services.Learn moreEnforcing your IPUnderstand infringement
Before taking legal action
Seizing counterfeit goods
Letter of demand
Resolution methods
Going to court
International Alternative Dispute Resolution
Mediation FAQs
Infringing on others' IP
More about IP infringementProtecting your IP online
IP insurance
Counterfeiting and piracy
Tools & resourcesTools & resourcesIf you are a self filer, attorney or a Qualified Person (QP) –this is the place to find our examination manuals, FAQs, case studies, search tools and more to help you further understand and research intellectual property.Learn moreOnline servicesOnline services latest news
Online services learning centre
Online services FAQ
Business to business
Case studiesPatents
Trade marks
Designs
Plant breeder's rights
IP glossary
Privacy
Last updated: 17 August 2020Our privacy policy summarises how we handle your personal information.
If you do not find the information you are looking for here, please read the full privacy policy.
You should read this policy if you are:
an applicant of an intellectual property (IP) right
an owner of an IP right
an attorney or agent for an applicant or owner
an individual whose personal information may be given to, or held, by IP Australia
a contractor, consultant, supplier or vendor of goods or services to IP Australia
a person seeking employment with IP Australia or
an IP Australia employee.
The Privacy Act
We comply with the Privacy Act 1988 (Privacy Act) when we handle personal information.
The Privacy Act contains 13 Australian Privacy Principles (APPs) which provide the rules for how agencies must handle your personal information, including how you can request access to, and correction of, that information.
Detailed information on the Privacy Act and APPs can be found on the website of the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (OAIC).
Personal information handling
We collect personal information for purposes directly related to our functions or activities under related IP rights’ legislation.
For a detailed list of personal information we hold please read the information digest.
Disclosure
We do not give your personal information to other government agencies or private-sector organisations unless one of the following applies:
you have consented
you  would reasonably expect, or have been told, that information of that kind is usually passed to those bodies or agencies
the disclosure is required or authorised by law (such as IP Australia’s rights’ legislation) or
a general permitted situation under the Privacy Act exists, such as: it will prevent or lessen a serious and imminent threat to somebody's life, health or safety, or to take appropriate action in relation to suspected unlawful activity or serious misconduct.
Overseas recipients of personal information
We also disclose personal information to overseas recipients with consent or where authorised or required by, or under law, or in accordance with an international treaty or convention.
Disposal of personal information
When the personal information that we collect is no longer required, we destroy or delete it in a secure manner, in accordance with the requirements of the Archives Act 1983 and IP Australia’s Record Disposal Authority.
Access and correction
You can request access to and correction of the personal information that we hold about you by contacting us.
Website usage and information policy
Our website contains links to other websites. IP Australia is not responsible for the content and the privacy practices of other websites.
We encourage individuals to examine each website's privacy policy.
Our website usage and information policy has more information about clickstream data, clicktails, cookies, tools used, email addresses and linking to external websites.
Privacy Impact Assessments
The Privacy (Australian Government Agencies – Governance) APP Code 2017 (Cth) (APP Code) requires that all Australian Government agencies, including IP Australia, conduct a Privacy Impact Assessment (PIA) for each high privacy risk project.
The table below lists the PIAs completed by IP Australia since the APP Code came into effect on 1 July 2018.
Privacy Impact Assessment
Date of Completion
TM-Link – Release 1
July 2018
Smart Trade Mark
July 2018
RIO Auto User Provisioning
April 2019
Online services - terms and conditions
Before you can register for our Online services, you must read, accept and agree to be legally bound by our Terms and conditions relating to the portal.
About usCareers
Data and research
Accountability and reporting
Doing business with us
Freedom of information
Agency overview
News and communityNews
Stay informed
IP rights searchPatents search (AusPat)
